The final step in your custom view creation
is adding interactivity. You can listen for user
input events including key presses, trackball movement, and
most importantly, screen touch events, all by overriding the
corresponding event handlers. Android supports tracking of up
to 11 individual contact points in what we
like to call, jazz hands mode which enables
you to complete complex and multi-finger interaction models. Now,
there's really no interaction required for a wind gauge, but
you can find out more about handling input events by checking
the motion event docs or the developer guide describing how to
create your own, fully interactive custom views, both from the [UNKNOWN]
below. Now, be careful not to let this new found power
go to your head. By definition, your users will have never
encountered your brand spanking new control. So learning how to use
it is going to add friction to the use of your app.
At the very least, it should behave consistently with the rest of the system
and you should avoid creating your own
versions of system controls. If it looks kind of
like a button and works kind of like a button, you should probably just go ahead
and use a button, but I think this non sequitur has gone on long enough.